# Carson Bruce

View at carson.kiwi

# I am passionate about creating simple beautiful apps.

I plan and deliver throughout the entire software development process, from when a project is imagined to its release. I've worked on a number of large projects, demonstrating my experience through a range of roles.

My key attributes include: problem solving, passion to learn and share, open mindedness, listening, and being a team player.

I am at home when working with and sharing JavaScript along with all the technologies and processes it enables.

Get in touch at

hello@carson.kiwi

### **Experience**

### **Forsyth Barr**

Dec 2022 - Mar 2024 (1 year)

I transitioned into Trove's parent company Forsyth Barr as a Senior Platform Engineer, joining a team focused on delivering a new platform. This product accelerates the development of FinTech products by supporting a suite of commonly used services by the industry. I managed design and implementation responsibilities in the team across several components including Identity and Access, SDK, Event Framework, and API Gateway.

#### **Trove**

Feb 2022 - Dec 2022 (10 months)

I worked with Trove as a Senior Financial Engineer. At Trove I helped launch Tempo, a FinTech product, by developing Financial Services and tooling to support the mobile application. The system centered around utilising AWS services, where I was able to quickly up skill in both Python and serverless development.

One of my early achievements at Trove included creating a performance testing suite that significantly improved confidence knowing the system was capable of handling loads well beyond launch expectations. This suite highlighted areas requiring attention which was able to feed into design and development for teams to improvement their designs, processes and implementations.

### Middleware NZ

Mar 2019 - Feb 2022 (3 years)

I worked with Middleware NZ as a Senior Developer. My focus shifted more towards API and microservice development aiming to broaden my technical experience. Numerous projects gave me practice across a variety of teams, technology and process. I adapted to each challenge and achieved positive outcomes for internal and external clients.

A core part of my time at Middleware NZ was focused delivering a product, the Open Banking Accelerator, which continues to be successfully implemented within multiple New Zealand banking clients. This product helps bank implement APIs and Security Profiles aligned with the New Zealand Open Banking specification.

### **Properly**

Nov 2017 - Mar 2019 (1 year)

I joined Properly to a team of 14, working across the world to provide tools and people to property owners and managers. After achieving our Series-A funding I saw the the company grow to over 50 members. I became the lead for the frontend team, together responsible for the multiple web apps of Properly. Beyond this role, I was involved with more of our engineering, design, and test team activities. This included: Web/Service implementation design, Full stack development, UX design, UI test automation, CI pipelines, Infrastructure design, and Infrastructure as code.

### **Solnet**

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017 (5 years)

I started with Solnet after graduating, joining the delivery team. I gained experience with a variety of clients, first as a front end developer, then as others: Devops developer, API developer and Automation tester. Later at my time in Solnet I mentored team members in JavaScript tooling and practices, through 1-on-1's and group presentations.

## **Education**

# **Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering, First Class Honours**

**Victoria University of Wellington** *2007-2012* 

### **Products and Projects**

#### **Platform**

Forsyth Barr

Forsyth Barr is a New Zealand leading investment firm who is also dedicated to investing in its own technology capability. Using the experience gained during the development of Tempo, the team implemented a platform product going live with its first integration within 8 months. My role involved design, direction, implementation focused on the delivery of The Platform with the majority of my time done working in a separate timezone between Canada and New Zealand.

- Lead the delivery of Javascript and Python SDKs.
- Moved rapidly from conception to first integration.
- Collaborated in The Platforms Security, API and Eventing architectures.
- Rooted myself in AWS thinking and its ecosystem.
- Provided feedback on product direction and scope.

### **Tempo**

Trove

Tempo is New Zealand's first guided retail investment app. A detached subsidiary of Forsyth Barr aimed to delivery this product to open a new set of customers and cement their technology capacity. This product successfully went to market and is now serving New Zealand. My role was flexible and included implementation design, mentoring, on call support and generally filling needs of the team and product.

- Rapidly up-skilled in Python and AWS development.
- Assisted with hiring phases of new recruits.
- Championed a performance testing suite steering the direction of several optimizations.
- Delivered the foundation of a Web version of the native apps.
- Mentored junior and intermediate team members.

### **Open Banking Accelerator Product**

Glueware (MWNZ)

The Open Banking Accelerator provides a standards conformant set of APIs banks can publish. With a small internal team, we created the product building on previous years experience within the Open Banking domain. My role included owning and delegating design, implementation and testing tasks along with reviewing and supporting other work in the team.

- · Owned technical leadership of microservice development and testing.
- Succeeded to prove value through delivery into multiple banks.
- · Promoted strong testing culture throughout team.
- Applied feedback from customers to improve experience and quality of the product.
- Worked closely with Product Owners to ensure team tasks and focus was aligned.
- Designed scalable and modular application using cloud and microservice patterns.

### **NZ COVID Pass Integration**

MoH (MWNZ)

This project was part of the Ministries COVID response to bring a verifiable COVID pass to people living or visiting New Zealand. Challenges included ensuring forecasted demand was handled and ensuring the APIs were appropriately secured given their sensitive nature. My role involved helping support more junior members of the team and aligning the work of the team with the delivery.

- Balanced quality of development under high time pressures.
- Enabled other developers and testers within the team by code reviews and pair programming.
- Communicated with client and other venders to ensure alignment of delivery.
- Supported design and achieved implementation of a highly available solution.

### Lending and Onboarding

BNZ (Solnet)

I joined a product team at BNZ to help transform their Lending and Onboarding systems, aiming to improve the experience for customers and bank users. This transformation was supported by a new way of delivery, promoting more modular systems design and implementation with supporting platforms and dev-ops processes. I shared the lead for the Front-end implementation of two major applications and a component library.

- Lead app design and development using a new front end technology.
- Promoted and adapted a UI component library for multiple applications.
- Guided Front-end developers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Guided UI Integration testers through best practices, process and tooling.

### **Employment Agreement Builder**

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment (Solnet)

EAB is an application for small to medium businesses to create new Employment agreements while learning about employment law with easy-to-digest content. EAB exceeded its objectives and was built, tested, and delivered in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD creating a suite of feature-complete integration and unit tests.
- Created a reusable forms solution, reused for a second MBIE Policy Builder app.
- Promoted a full stack Javascript solution supported by docker.
- Implemented Node.js micro service handling 10x expected load.
- Implemented a pipeline that performed automated testing and releases.

### **Online Banking**

Westpac (Solnet)

I was part of a Westpac team with a goal to improve their online banking experience. I supported the developers of the project, mediating communications between development teams. I improved automation in local, development, and test environments helping developers become more autonomous. After two months my role extended to a technical lead of a team of five, responsible for feature development in the middleware.

- Trusted as the custodian of environments relied on by a team of 60+.
- Lead and mentor of a team of five.
- Proposed and owned developer tooling and experience improvements.
- Implemented a Javascript framework that supported other teams.
- Took ownership for the security features of the client.

hello@carson.kiwi github.com/Kauabunga nz.linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce